Register of the Roy A. Childs papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- Speeches and Writings, 1933-1994
  - Research Notes, 1933-1992
    - Objectivism, 1986-1989 (Text : 19: 4)
    - Raico, Ralph, circa 1981 (Text : 19: 5)
    - Rand, Ayn, 1983-1989 (Text : 19: 6)
    - Rand, Ayn, 1976-1978 (Text : 19: 7)
    - Rand, Ayn, 1992 (Text : 20: 1)
    - Rand, Ayn, 1978-1986 (Text : 20: 2)
    - Rand, Ayn, 1987 (Text : 20: 3)
    - Rand, Ayn, 1982 (Text : 20: 4)
    - Ravenal, Earl C., 1983 (Text : 20: 5-6)
    - Rothbard, Murray N., 1970-1993 (Text : 20: 7)
    - Rothbard, Murray N., 1957-1982 (Text : 21: 1)
    - Rothbard, Murray N., 1962-1980 (Text : 21: 2)
    - Thomas S. Szasz Award, 1990-1991 (Text : 21: 3)
    - Whole Libertarian Catalogue, 1976 (Text : 21: 4)
    - Wild, Earl, 1991 (Text : 21: 5)
    - Will, George, 1981 (Text : 21: 6)
    - Williams, Walter E., 1981 (Text : 21: 7)
    - World Liberty Project, 1990 (Text : 21: 8)
    - Young Americans for Freedom, 1978-1979 (Text : 21: 9)
  - Writings by Others, 1945-1992
    Comprised of writings by various authors with whom Roy A. Childs was familiar or associated. Some of the authors submitted their writing to Childs in hopes that he would do some editing work and provide feedback. Further included are two books in which Roy A. Childs took marginalia notes. One of those is a 1957 copy of Ayn Rand’s book Atlas Shrugged, and the other is a 1974 copy of Robert Nozick's book Anarchy, State and Utopia.
    - Allport, Glen, 1987 (Text : 22: 1)
    - Anderson, Annelise, 1990 (Text : 22: 2)
    - Anderson, Annelise, and Bark, Dennis L., 1988 (Text : 22: 3-4)
    - Anderson, Martin, circa 1990 (Text : 22: 5)
    - Armentano, D. T., 1986 (Text : 22: 6)
    - Badhwar, Neera Kapur, 1985 (Text : 22: 7)
    - Ball, William B., 1977 (Text : 22: 8)
    - Bandow, Doug, 1991 (Text : 22: 9)
    - Barnett, Randy E., 1984 (Text : 22: 10)
    - Bastiat, Frederic, 1986 (Text : 22: 11)
    - Benesch, Alvin M., 1984-1989 (Text : 22: 12)
    - "Between Instinct and Reason,", circa 1970 (Text : 22: 13)
    - Blanshard, Brand, circa 1980 (Text : 23: 1)
    - Block, Walter, circa 1980 (Text : 23: 2-5)
    - Boaz, David, circa 1986 (Text : 23: 6)
    - Books, 1984 (Text : 23: 7)
    - Bradford, R. W., 1989 (Text : 23: 8)
    - Branden, Barbara, 1959 (Text : 23: 9)
    - Branden, Nathaniel, 1990 (Text : 24: 1)
    - Brown, David M., circa 1990 (Text : 24: 2)
    - Bukovsky, Vladimir, 1978 (Text : 24: 3)
    - Cato Institute, 1981-1984 (Text : 24: 4)
    - Chapman, Stephen, 1982-1988 (Text : 24: 5)
    - "Committee for Peace and Free Trade,", circa 1980 (Text : 24: 6)
    - Constant, Benjamin, 1987-1988 (Text : 24: 7-8)
    - Cordato, Roy E., circa 1980 (Text : 24: 9)
    - Cordato, Roy E., circa 1980 (Text : 25: 1)
    - Cornuelle, Richard, circa 1980 (Text : 25: 2)
    - Cott, Lawrence V., circa 1980 (Text : 25: 3)
    - Cowen, Tyler, circa 1990 (Text : 25: 4)
    - "Declaration of Chinese Patriots,", 1989 (Text : 25: 6)
    - Demsetz, Harold, circa 1980 (Text : 25: 7)
    - Dennis, Richard J., 1991-1992 (Text : 25: 8)
    - Dentinger, John, circa 1983 (Text : 25: 9)
    - Diaz, Ramon P., 1973 (Text : 25: 10)
    - Dines, James, 1978-1979 (Text : 25: 11)
    - Doenecke, Justus D., 1981 (Text : 25: 12)
    - Ebeling, Richard M., circa 1980 (Text : 25: 13)
    - Ebeling, Richard M., circa 1980 (Text : 26: 1-3)
    - Efron, Edith, 1992 (Text : 26: 4)
    - "The Enemy of Being Is Having,", circa 1980 (Text : 26: 5)
    - Epstein, Richard A., 1988-1991 (Text : 26: 6-7)
    - Epstein, Richard A., 1988-1991 (Text : 27: 1)
    - Evers, Bill, circa 1970 (Text : 27: 2)
    - Ferns, Harry S., 1977 (Text : 27: 3)
    - Flynn, John T., 1956 (Text : 27: 4)
    - Friedman, Milton, 1974 (Text : 27: 5)
    - Friedman, Milton, 1987 (Text : 27: 6)
    - Goss, Kristin A., 1992 (Text : 27: 7)
    - Graves, Leslie, 1991 (Text : 27: 8)
    - Greaves, Bettina Bien, 1988 (Text : 27: 9)
    - Grenier, Richard, 1986 (Text : 27: 10)
    - Grinder, Walter E., 1975 (Text : 27: 11)
    - Hagel, John, III, 1975 (Text : 27: 12)
    - Halliday, Roy, circa 1980 (Text : 27: 13)
    - Hamowy, Ronald, 1964 (Text : 27: 14)
    - Hanke, Steve H., and Walters, Alan A., 1991 (Text : 27: 15)
    - Hanke, Steve H., and Walters, Alan A., 1991 (Text : 28: 1)
    - Harper, F. A., 1966-1968 (Text : 28: 2)
    - Hayek, Friedrich, 1988 (Text : 28: 3)
    - Hayek, Friedrich, 1990 (Text : 28: 4)
    - Hazlitt, Henry, 1978 (Text : 28: 5)
    - Heilbroner, Robert L., 1976 (Text : 28: 6)
    - Hersh, Seymour M., 1982 (Text : 28: 7)
    - Hess, Karl, Jr., circa 1970 (Text : 28: 8-10)
    - Hodges, Richard, 1987 (Text : 29: 1)
    - Horn, Carl, 1985 (Text : 29: 2)
    - Horowitz, Carl, circa 1990 (Text : 29: 3)
    - Horsman, Michael, 1984 (Text : 29: 4)
    - Hospers, John, circa 1990 (Text : 29: 5)
    - Howell, Leon, 1967 (Text : 29: 6)
    - Hubert, Peter, 1987 (Text : 29: 7)
    - Huberman, Bernardo A., 1989 (Text : 29: 8)
    - Hummel, Jeffrey Rogers, 1987 (Text : 29: 9)
    - Kahn, Roger, 1990 (Text : 29: 10)
    - Kass, Leon R., 1990 (Text : 29: 11)
    - Kelley, David, circa 1980 (Text : 29: 12)
    - Kibbe, Matthew B., circa 1980 (Text : 29: 13)
    - Kirk, Russell, 1988 (Text : 29: 14)
    - Kirzner, Israel M., 1990 (Text : 29: 15)
    - Klein, Daniel B., 1989-1991 (Text : 29: 16)
    - Koch, Charles, 1979, 1992 (Text : 29: 17)
    - Kozinski, Alex, 1980 (Text : 29: 18)
    - Kramnick, Isaac, 1975 (Text : 29: 19)
    - Kristol, Irving, 1978 (Text : 29: 20)
    - Lachmann, Ludwig, 1974-1984 (Text : 29: 21)
    - Lane, Rose Wilder, 1945 (Text : 29: 22)
    - Lavoie, Donald C., 1981 (Text : 29: 23)
    - Lavoie, Donald C., 1981 (Text : 30: 1-2)
    - Lee, Albert, 1987 (Text : 30: 3)
    - Leef, George C., circa 1980 (Text : 30: 4)
    - LeFevre, Robert, circa 1980 (Text : 30: 5)
    - The Libertarian Newsletter, 1986-1988 (Text : 30: 6)
    - Liggio, Leonard P., 1977-1986 (Text : 30: 7)
    - Lindberg, Tod, circa 1980 (Text : 30: 8)
    - Lomasky, Loren, 1987 (Text : 30: 9)
    - Lukacs, John, 1982 (Text : 30: 10)
    - Lynch, Frederick R., 1989 (Text : 30: 11)
    - Machan, Tibor, 1987 (Text : 31: 1)
    - McElroy, Wendy, circa 1980 (Text : 31: 2)
    - Mencken, H. L., 1989 (Text : 31: 3)
    - Merrill, Ronald E., 1988 (Text : 31: 4-5)
    - Miller, Fred D. Jr., circa 1980 (Text : 31: 6)
    - Milliere, Guy, 1989 (Text : 31: 7)
    - Miscellaneous articles and reprints, circa 1987 (Text : 31: 8)
    - Mon, Stormy, 1987 (Text : 32: 1)
    - Mosher, Steven W., 1990 (Text : 32: 2)
    - Murray, Charles, 1988 (Text : 32: 3)
    - Nisbet, Robert A., 1976 (Text : 32: 4)
    - Nock, Albert Jay, circa 1990 (Text : 32: 5)
    - Norton, David L., circa 1980 (Text : 32: 6)
    - Nozick, Robert, 1974 (Text : 32: 7)
    - Nozick, Robert, 1986 (Text : 32: 8-9)
    - Nozick, Robert, 1986 (Text : 33: 1-2)
    - "Open Letter to the Anti-draft Movement,", circa 1970 (Text : 33: 3)
    - "Open Letter to Guyanese Professionals,", circa 1970 (Text : 33: 4)
    - Pack, Spencer J., 1989 (Text : 33: 5-7)
    - Palmer, Tom G., circa 1980 (Text : 33: 8)
    - Peden, Joseph, circa 1980 (Text : 34: 1)
    - Peikoff, Leonard, 1991 (Text : 34: 2)
    - Pilon, Roger, 1978-1988 (Text : 34: 3-5)
    - Podhoretz, Norman, 1976 (Text : 34: 6)
    - Porter, Tom, circa 1980 (Text : 34: 7)
    - Presley, Sharon Lee, 1985 (Text : 34: 8)
    - "The Public Goods Argument,", circa 1990 (Text : 34: 9)
    - Rabushka, Alvin, 1991 (Text : 34: 10)
    - Raico, Ralph, 1988 (Text : 34: 11)
    - Raimondo, Justin, circa 1982 (Text : 35: 1-3)
    - Raimondo, Justin, 1991 (Text : 35: 4)
    - Rand, Ayn, 1957 (Text : 35: 5)
    - Rand, Ayn, 1961-1978 (Text : 35: 6)
    - Rasmussen, Douglas B., circa 1980 (Text : 36: 1)
    - Ravenal, Earl C., 1986 (Text : 36: 2)
    - Read, Leonard E., 1958 (Text : 36: 3)
    - Reading list and bibliography - United States history, 1968 (Text : 36: 4)
    - Reese, David A., 1987 (Text : 36: 5)
    - Reisman, George, 1961-1990 (Text : 36: 6)
    - Review of Austrian Economics, 1987-1997 (Text : 36: 7-9)
    - Reynolds, Alan, 1979 (Text : 36: 10)
    - Richman, Sheldon L., 1990-1991 (Text : 37: 1)
    - Rielly, John E., 1982 (Text : 37: 2)
    - Riggenbach, Jeff, 1979-1987 (Text : 37: 3)
    - Robbins, James, 1991 (Text : 37: 4)
    - Robbins, Lionel, circa 1980 (Text : 37: 5)
    - Rothbard, Murray N., circa 1970 (Text : 37: 6-7)
    - Ryerson, Andre, circa 1986 (Text : 37: 8)
    - Sadowsky, James, S. J., circa 1980 (Text : 37: 9)
    - Salerno, Joseph T., 1975 (Text : 37: 8)
    - Sartori, Giovanni, 1976 (Text : 37: 9)
    - Scheb, Joe J., 1969 (Text : 38: 1)
    - Schuck, Peter, H., 1976 (Text : 38: 2)
    - Schuler, Kurt, 1985 (Text : 38: 3)
    - Schuler, William C., 1991 (Text : 38: 4)
    - Seldon, Peter, circa 1980 (Text : 38: 5)
    - Selgin, George, 1991 (Text : 38: 6)
    - Sennholz, Hans F., 1990 (Text : 38: 7)
    - Shaffer, Butler D., 1976 (Text : 38: 8)
    - Shannon, Russell, 1987 (Text : 38: 9)
    - Shenoy, Sudha R., 1975 (Text : 38: 10)
    - Smith, Kay Nolte, circa 1990 (Text : 38: 11-13)
    - Smith, Marcella, circa 1990 (Text : 39: 1)
    - Sobran, Joseph P., circa 1990 (Text : 39: 2)
    - Spinney, Franklin C., circa 1980 (Text : 39: 3)
    - Stigler, Geroge J., 1963 (Text : 39: 4)
    - Swan, George Steven, 1987 (Text : 39: 5)
    - Szasz, Thomas, circa 1980 (Text : 39: 6-8)
    - Taylor, Jeremy, 1966 (Text : 39: 9)
    - Taylor, Joan Kennedy, 1987 (Text : 39: 10)
    - Taylor, John, circa 1980 (Text : 39: 11)
    - Thierry, Augustin, circa 1981 (Text : 39: 12)
    - Toohey, John J., circa 1980 (Text : 40: 1-2)
    - Tucker, Robert W., 1983 (Text : 40: 3)
    - Turiano, Mark, 1992 (Text : 40: 4)
    - Van Den Haad, Ernest, 1975 (Text : 40: 5)
    - Vargas, Mario, 1987 (Text : 40: 6)
    - Veatch, Henry, 1985 (Text : 40: 7)
    - Wagner, Richard E., 1989 (Text : 40: 8)
    - Walker, Graham, 1986 (Text : 40: 9)
    - Walters, Alan, 1978 (Text : 40: 10)
    - Wang, Hao, circa 1980 (Text : 40: 11)
    - Ward, Geoffrey C., 1989 (Text : 40: 12)
    - Weinburg, Mark, 1978 (Text : 40: 13)
    - "What Is 'Social Justice' ?", circa 1980 (Text : 40: 14)
    - Williams, Walter E., circa 1980 (Text : 40: 15)
    - Williams, Walter E., circa 1980 (Text : 41: 1)
    - Writings forwarded by friends and associates, 1988-1991 (Text : 41: 2)
    - Unidentified writings, circa 1980 (Text : 41: 3)
  - Writings, circa 1960 - 1994
    Materials in this series are composed of writings by Roy A. Childs on various topics that were of interest to him. The writings are organized mainly by the title of the work with some writings being organized by overall concepts or years in which they were composed. The subseries also includes a number of unpublished working manuscripts and a final copy of a book titled Liberty Against Power: Essays by Roy A. Childs, which was edited by his close friend and colleague, Joan Kennedy Taylor.
    - "Anarchist Illusions,", circa 1970 (Text : 41: 4)
    - "Anarchism and Justice,", 1971 (Text : 41: 5-7)
    - "Autarchy and the Statist,", 1968 (Text : 41: 8)
    - "Ayn Rand 1905-1982," (Text : 41: 9)
    - "Ayn Rand and the Libertarian Movement,", circa 1980 (Text : 41: 10)
    - Ayn Rand, 1986 (Text : 41: 11)
    - "The Battle for the Country: Ronald Reagan Ascends to Power,", circa 1981 (Text : 42: 1)
    - "Battling the Drug War,", circa 1987 (Text : 42: 2)
    - "Big Business and the Rise of American Statism: A Revisionist History,", circa 1980 (Text : 42: 3)
    - "Bigotry and Tolerance,", 1981 (Text : 42: 4)
    - "Capitalism and Its Discontents,", 1978 (Text : 42: 5)
    - "The Contradiction in Objectivism,", 1968 (Text : 42: 6)
    - "Crime in the Cities: the Drug Connection,", 1986 (Text : 42: 7)
    - "Cuba and the Hawks,", 1979 (Text : 42: 8)
    - "The Defense of the Capitalism in Our Time,", circa 1990 (Text : 42: 9)
    - "Destabilizing America's Allies,", 1981 (Text : 42: 10)
    - "Deterrence and the MX,", circa 1980 (Text : 42: 11)
    - "Edith Efron, Newstwister: The Case for Eclectic Strategy,", 1978 (Text : 42: 12)
    - Editorials, 1977-1978 (Text : 42: 13)
    - "The Epistemological Basis of Anarchism: An Open Letter to Objectivists and Libertarians,", circa 1980 (Text : 42: 14)
    - "The Ethics of Liberty,", circa 1977 (Text : 42: 15)
    - Foreign policy article for Ed Clark's campaign book, 1980 (Text : 42: 16)
    - "The Invisible Hand Strikes Back,", 1977 (Text : 42: 17)
    - "The Iranian Drama,", circa 1980 (Text : 42: 18)
    - "Land Reform and the Entitlement Theory of Justice,", 1976 (Text : 42: 19)
    - "The Landslide Before the Storm,", 1981 (Text : 42: 20)
    - Libertarian Review, 1977-1981 (Text : 42: 21)
    - "The Libertarian Viewpoint,", circa 1980 (Text : 43: 1)
    - "Liberty Against Power,", 1975 (Text : 43: 2)
    - Liberty Against Power: Essays by Roy A. Childs, Jr., 1994 (Text : 43: 3)
    - Liberty Against Power: Essays by Roy A. Childs, Jr., edited by Joan Kennedy Taylor, 1994 (Text : 43: 4-7)
    - Liberty Against Power: Essays by Roy A. Childs, Jr., edited by Joan Kennedy Taylor, 1994 (Text : 44: 1-4)
    - "The Myth of Progressive Reform,", 1981 (Text : 44: 5)
    - "The Mythology of Heroin,", 1983 (Text : 44: 6)
    - "Nato: The Case for Disengagement,", circa 1980 (Text : 44: 7)
    - "The New Authoritarians,", 1980 (Text : 44: 8)
    - "Night of Fury,", 1979 (Text : 44: 9)
    - "A Note on Revolution,", circa 1970 (Text : 44: 10)
    - Notes, circa 1970 (Text : 44: 11)
    - Notes, circa 1970 (Text : 45: 1-4)
    - Notes, circa 1980 (Text : 45: 5)
    - "Objective Law and Anarchism,", circa 1970 (Text : 45: 6)
    - "On Drugs,", 1983-1987 (Text : 45: 7)
    - "An Open Letter to Ayn Rand: Objectivists and the State,", circa 1969 (Text : 45: 8)
    - [other people's work he was involved with], 1987-1991 (Text : 45: 9)
    - "Phyllis Schlafly Rides Again,", 1978 (Text : 45: 10)
    - "Pine Tree Featrues,", 1968 (Text : 45: 11)
    - "Playing the China Card,", 1979 (Text : 45: 12)
    - "Poland and Liberty,", circa 1980 (Text : 46: 1-2)
    - "Professor Kroy on Contract and Freedom: Comment,", 1977 (Text : 46: 3)
    - "Rand and the Movement,", 1982 (Text : 46: 4)
    - Reason Column - Pilot Episode, 1988 (Text : 46: 5)
    - Reviews, 1970-1972 (Text : 46: 6)
    - "Shattered Kristol: Capitalism and Its Discontents,", circa 1980 (Text : 46: 7)
    - "Strangelove Returns,", 1980 (Text : 46: 8)
    - "Thomas Szasz: An Assessment,", 1990 (Text : 46: 9)
    - "A Time for Truth,", circa 1980 (Text : 46: 10)
    - "Toward a Rational Philosophy of History,", circa 1980 (Text : 46: 11)
    - [very young (school?) papers,], circa 1960 (Text : 46: 12)
    - Writings composed in 1970 (Text : 46: 13)
    - Writings composed in 1971 (Text : 46: 14)
    - Miscellaneous, circa 1980 (Text : 46: 15)